Guide to the Eugène and Maria Jolas Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Maria Jolas - Writings, 1883-1983; Series VIII; 1.75; (4 boxes)
  - AUTOBIOGRAPHY
    - Photographs
      - Louisville, Kentucky [with enclosure], ca. 1883-97 (Box 39, Folder 887)
    - Research material
      - Clippings
        - Acquaintances, 1971-82 (Box 39, Folder 888)
        - Book reviews, n.d.
        - Politics, 1974, 1976, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 889)
        - Profiles of Maria Jolas, 1970, 1972
      - Genealogy, 1965-76, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 890)
      - Thomas Jefferson, 1974, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 891)
      - St. James Court in Retrospective by Marguerite Gifford, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 892)
      - Warm Springs, Virginia, 1976, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 893)
    - Early drafts, holograph with typescript corrections
      - Complete book draft, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 894-95)
      - Chapters
        - Introduction - Childhood, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 896)
        - Childhood, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 897)
        - Schooling, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 898)
        - Sailing to Germany, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 899)
        - Studying in Germany, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 900)
        - Life after Colombey, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 901)
        - Miscellaneous pages, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 902)
    - Later drafts, typescript and typescript photocopy
      - Outline, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 903)
      - Book, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 904-06)
      - Chapters
        - Introduction, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 907)
        - Berlin to Paris, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 908)
        - Paris, 1919-1927 [with letter], 1982 (Box 41, Folder 909)
        - Enddream, 1975 Aug (Box 41, Folder 910)
      - Miscellaneous pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 911)
    - Notebook
      - Notebook, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 912)
    - Notes
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 913)
  - NOTEBOOKS
    - [Jimmy Carter and Cambodia]
      See: Poems - "Songs of Hoary Innocence" - Notebook
    - [The École bilingue de Neuilly during World War II], 1941 Jan 11 (Box 41, Folder 914)
    - [Freud], n.d. (Box 41, Folder 915)
    - "L'idée de culture - Jean Wahl", 1947 (Box 41, Folder 916)
    - [Notes on Joyce and Final Days at St. Gérand-le-Puy] (Box 41, Folder 917)
    - [Re: Refusals on translations of French authors], n.d. (Box 41, Folder 918)
    - "Sartre", 1947 (Box 41, Folder 919)
    - "War Diary", 1940 (Box 41, Folder 920)
  - OPEN LETTERS
    - "Chers amis français...", typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 921)
    - To the Courier Journal, Louisville, Kentucky, typescript [with response letter], 1941 (Box 41, Folder 922)
    - "Dear American Friends..."," typescript carbon, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 923)
    - [Femmes Françaises], typescript [with response letter], 1947 (Box 41, Folder 924)
    - "James Joyce and his Fellow Dubliners" [Letter to the London Times ], typescript carbon, 1972 Feb 4 (Box 41, Folder 925)
    - "Je vous raconte notre odyssée..."," typescript, 1941 Apr 28 (Box 41, Folder 926)
    - "Joyce as Revolutionary" [Letter to The New Republic ] printed page, 1942 Nov 9 (Box 41, Folder 927)
    - To the New York Evening Post, typescript carbons, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 928)
    - To the New York Herald-Tribune, typescript, carbon, 1944 Feb 2 (Box 41, Folder 929)
    - To the New York Times, typescript carbon [with responses], 1941-42 (Box 41, Folder 930)
    - "Paris Letters," typescript, carbon, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 931)
    - To the Saturday Review of Literature, typescript carbon, 1941 Jan 28 (Box 41, Folder 932)
    - To the Times Literary Supplement, holograph and printed page, 1981 Dec 1 (Box 41, Folder 933)
      See also: Subject Files - Nathalie Sarraute - Clippings
  - POEMS
    - "In France," holograph photocopy, 1982 May (Box 41, Folder 934)
    - "Songs of Hoary Innocence"
      - Notebook, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 935)
      - typescript, corrected, n.d.
  - RADIO ADDRESSES
    - "Radio and the Child" - WEVD, typescript photocopy, corrected, 1941 May (Box 41, Folder 936)
    - "The Fight for Freedom Committee" - WCNH, typescript, photocopy, 1941 May 3 (Box 41, Folder 937)
    - "Fighting French Exhibition" - WNYC, typescript, corrected, 1942 Nov (Box 41, Folder 938)
    - [Fourth of July] - WCNW, typescript carbon, corrected, 1941 Jul 14 (Box 41, Folder 939)
    - "The French Home," - NBC, typescript, carbon, 1945 May (Box 41, Folder 940)
    - [Introduction for Maria Jolas], typescript, carbon, 1941 Aug 1 (Box 41, Folder 941)
    - "Memorial Day" - WCNW, typescript, carbon, 1941 May 30 (Box 41, Folder 942)
  - SCHOOL PRESENTATIONS
    - "Récits et chants du folklore américain" typescript [with response letters], 1947 Mar 5 (Box 41, Folder 943)
  - SPEECHES
    - "Disque pour le Special Events Department," typescript, mimeograph, 1941 Oct 15 (Box 41, Folder 944)
    - [Joyce Centenary Speech], holograph, 1982 Jun 12 (Box 41, Folder 945)
    - "Possible postlude" [on Joyce], typescript, corrected, ca. 1975 (Box 41, Folder 946)
    - "When I returned to America..."," typescript, corrected, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 947)
    - [Women's International Exposition], typescript, corrected, 1943 Nov (Box 41, Folder 948)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Boyle, Kay "Approchez-Vous Mesdames"
      See: Maria Jolas - Correspondence, folder 540
    - Colum, Padraic "Images of Departure," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 949)
    - Duthuit, Georges Le serpent dans la galère, French text, typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 949a)
    - Jolas, Charles "Je fais parti [sic] des Compagnons de France..."," extract of letter, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 950)
    - Kearney, Richard and J. S. O'Leary "Avant-Propos" [Heidegger], typescript photocopy, 1979 Jun (Box 42, Folder 951)
    - Lacan, Jacques "Propos sur la Causalité Psychique," typescript, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 951a)
    - Lippmann, Walter What is wanted from France booklet, ca. 1942 (Box 42, Folder 952)
    - Marie-Antoinette, Soeur "Montluzin: Journées tragiques des 19 et 20 Juin 1940," typescript, carbon, n.d.
    - Masson, André "Terre Morte," holograph, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 952a)
      [Includes calling card from Rose
      Masson and Christmas print by André
      Masson, 1942]
    - McMillan, Dougald Transition: The History of a Literary Era, 1927-1938
      - Clipping, 1975 Oct 25 (Box 42, Folder 953)
      - Correspondence [including corrections by Maria Jolas], 1972-74 (Box 42, Folder 954)
        See also: Series VII, Box 35, folder 709
      - Note and corrections by Maria Jolas (Box 42, Folder 955)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, [1973] (Box 42, Folder 956-57)
    - Vidal-Naquet, Pierre "Le Kampuchea démocratique devant le Tribunal des Nations Unies," typescript, photocopy corrected, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 958)
- Maria Jolas - Translations, 1926-1982; Series IX; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series IX is arranged alphabetically by original author or title of each work.
  - Les Années 20 catalogue, American Cultural Center, Paris
    - French text, corrected, proof, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 959)
  - Bachelard, Gaston
    - "Poétique de l'espace"
      - English translation notebook, [1968] (Box 43, Folder 960)
      - English translation pages, typescript, corrected, [1968]
      - Memos, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 961)
      - Note pages, n.d.
    - "Poétique de la rêverie"
      - Translation notebook, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 962)
  - Bataille, Georges
    - "The Economic Role of the Gift: Potlatch"
      - English translation, typescript carbon, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 963)
  - Bayet, Albert
    - "French Response to Arthur Koestler"
      - Letter, 1942 Feb 23 (Box 43, Folder 964)
      - French text, typescript carbon, [1942]
      - English translation, [1942]
  - Bedside Book of Famous French Stories
    - Dustjacket, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 965)
  - Breton, André
    - Martinique Today
      - Correspondence (Box 43, Folder 966)
      - French text, typescript carbon and holograph
      - English translation, typescript, corrected, n.d.
  - Cain, Julien
    - The Lithographs of Chagall
      - Correspondence, 1960, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 967)
      - French text, proof, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 968)
      - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 969)
      - English translation, typescript, corrected, [1960] (Box 43, Folder 970)
      - English translation, galley proof, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 971)
  - Char, René
    - Chants de la Balandrane
      - English translations, typescript, corrected, [1977] (Box 43, Folder 972)
  - Cotereau, Jean
    - L'Eglise a-t-elle collaboré?
      - French text, [1946] (Box 43, Folder 973)
        See also: Michel Riquet - Le chrétien face à l'argent, Box 44, folder 1005
      - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 43, Folder 974)
  - Erben, Walter
    - Joan Miró
      - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 975)
  - Franck, Nino
    - Les Lettres italiennes de 1870 à nos Jours
      - French text, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 976)
  - Giedion-Welcker, Carola
    - Constantin Brancusi
      - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 43, Folder 977)
      - Exhibition pamphlet, 1926
      - Notebooks, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 978)
      - English translation pages, typescript, corrected [with notes], 1958-59
  - Heine, Heinrich
    - "A Young Man Loves a Maiden..."
      - English translation, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 979)
  - Hofmannsthal, Hugo von
    - A Few Poems
      - Correspondence, 1977-81 (Box 43, Folder 980)
        [includes: James Stern, Wallace
        Irwin, Jane Lidderdale, André
        Boucourechliev, Robert Day, Elise
        and Richard Marienstras and George
        Braziller
      - Notes, 1976-77 (Box 43, Folder 981)
      - Photographs, 1976
      - Introductory text drafts, typescript, corrected, [1977] (Box 43, Folder 982)
      - German poems with English translations, typescript, corrected, [1977] (Box 43, Folder 983)
      - Text proofs, [1977] (Box 44, Folder 984)
      - Cover illustration by Claire Illouz
        See: Oversize, Box 68, folder 1584
      - Printed text, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 985)
  - Jaulin, Robert
    - La Mort Sara
      - Correspondence [including University of Chicago Press and Robert Jaulin], 1969-73 (Box 44, Folder 986)
      - Interview article with Robert Jaulin, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 987)
      - French text - "Avertissement," typescript photocopy, [1970] (Box 44, Folder 988)
      - Review of French text, Critique, 1967 Jun (Box 44, Folder 989)
      - English translation - A, typescript, corrected, photocopy, [1972] (Box 44, Folder 990)
      - English translation - B, typescript carbon, [1972] (Box 44, Folder 991-92)
  - Lefort, Claude
    - "Solzhenitsyn: A Comment on the Gulag Archipelago"
      - Notebook, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 993)
  - Magny, Claude-Edmonde
    - "A Time of Reflective Thought,"
      - English translation, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 993a)
  - Maritain, Jacques
    - Rouault
      - English translation, holograph, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 994)
      - Book catalogue, 1961
  - Masson, André
    - "Courbet, la réaliste fabuleux" Cahiers du Sud
      - French text, printed version, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 995)
    - "De la profondeur" Cahiers du Sud
      - French text, printed version, n.d.
    - "Notes about My Paintings"
      - Translation notebook, [1955] (Box 44, Folder 996)
      - English translation [with translator's note], [1955]
    - "Peinture et rhétorique" Cahiers du Sud
      - French text, printed version, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 997)
    - "Révélation de la peinture antique" Cahiers du Sud
      - French text, n.d.
  - Mauriac, Claude
    - Le Dîner en ville
      - Editor's reports, 1959 (Box 44, Folder 998)
  - Merleau-Ponty, Maurice
    - The Doubt of Cézanne
      - English translation pages, typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 999)
  - Meyer, Franz
    - "Ben Nicholson"
      - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 1000)
      - Notebook, 1959
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1001)
      - English translation, typescript carbon, corrected, 1960
    - Marc Chagall
      - Correspondence [including Gabrielle Buffet-Picabia and Franz Meyer], 1957, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1002)
      - English translation pages, typescript, corrected, [1957] (Box 44, Folder 1003)
      - Notes, n.d.
      - English translation, galley proof, [1957] (Box 44, Folder 1004)
  - Riquet, Michel, S.J.
    - Le chrétien face à l'argent
      - French text, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 1005)
      - Clippings, 1948
  - Multilingual Poets Project
    - Outline, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1006)
    - Poems, with letters and profiles of poets
    - Goll, Yvan
      - "Atom Elegy," printed text, n.d.
      - "The Eye of Eyes," Iconograph printed text, 1946
      - Letter with résumé, 1948 Jul 7
      - "Le Chant de Raziel," typescript, n.d.
      - "Mon Père, Le Feu, typescript, n.d.
      - "Jean Sans Terre Le Double" with "Jean Sans Terre Aborde au Dernier Port," La Nouvelle Relève printed text, n.d.
      - "Der Heilege Leib," typescript carbon, n.d.
      - "Die Hochöfen des Schmerzes," typescript carbon
      - "Rosentum," typescript carbon, n.d.
      - "Bluthund," typescript carbon
      - "Das Wasserjahr," typescript carbon, n.d.
    - [Roditi, Edouard]
      - Note to Eugène Jolas, n.d.
      - "Le poème perpetuel," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "Prière," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "Chanson," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "Chanson," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "Usage externe," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "Sortilège," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "La Ballade de Sankt Pauli," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "La Vallée des Rois," typescript, corrected, n.d.
      - "Three Laments," typescript carbon, 1938-40
      - "Avenue des Champs-Élysees," typescript carbon, 1940
      - "The Western World," typescript carbon, 1940
      - "The Plots," typescript carbon, 1941
      - "A Parisian in Kansas City," typescript carbon, 1942
      - "Four Allegories of Love," typescript carbon, 1943
      - "Manhattan Novelettes," typescript carbon, 1943
    - Jolas, Eugène
      - "Die Metamorphose" with "Nach dem Traum..."," printed text, n.d.
    - Wahl, Jean [all typescript, corrected], n.d.
      "Sometimes I Skip Over Time"
      "Fiery Presence"
      "Praying for God"
      "A Little Boy Found"
      "The Soul Leaves the Skies"
      "After Travelling on Earth"
      "An Angel"
      "Angel and Beast"
      "The Tree"
      "Ecstasies"
  - Nietzsche, Friedrich
    - "Das Trunkene Lied"
      - English translation, typescript, corrected, 1976-77 (Box 44, Folder 1007)
  - [Poster Book]
    - French text, galley proof
    - English translation, typescript carbon, corrected [with correspondence], [1959] (Box 44, Folder 1008)
    - English translation, galley proof
  - Rilke, Rainer Maria
    - [Various poems]
      - German texts with English translations, typescripts, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1009)
      - "An die Musik" "Aus dem Umkreis: Nächte" "Nachthimmel and Sternfall" "Immer weider, ob wir der Liebe..."
  - Rougemont, Denis de
    - "German Romanticism"
      - English translation, Chimera, 1945 (Box 44, Folder 1010)
  - Sarraute, Nathalie
    - Disent les imbéciles
      - English translation notebook, typescript, corrected, [1976] (Box 44, Folder 1011)
    - Entre la vie et la mort
      - French text, printed version [with enclosures], [1968] (Box 45, Folder 1012)
      - English translation notebook, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1013)
      - English translation book reviews, 1969-70 (Box 45, Folder 1014)
    - L'ère du soupçon
      - Correspondence, 1950 Dec 1 (Box 45, Folder 1015)
      - French text, Les Temps Modernes, 1950 Feb
      - English translations, typescripts carbon, corrected, [1950] (Box 45, Folder 1016)
    - "Flaubert le précurseur"
      - French text, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1017)
      - English translation, typescript carbon, corrected, 1965 (Box 45, Folder 1018)
    - Les fruits d'or
      - French text book reviews, 1963 (Box 45, Folder 1019)
      - English translation notebook, holograph, corrected, [1963] (Box 45, Folder 1020-21)
    - It's Beautiful
      - English translation notebook, holograph, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 1022)
      - English translation, typescript, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 1023)
    - Martereau
      - English translation, typescript carbon, corrected, ca. 1959 (Box 46, Folder 1024)
      - Book jacket, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1025)
      - Press release, n.d.
      - Book reviews, 1953-60
    - Le planetarium
      - Note from French text, 1959 (Box 46, Folder 1026)
      - [Cover blurb] English translation, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1027)
      - Advertisements and book reviews, 1959, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1028)
    - Portrait d'un inconnu
      - English translation notebook, holograph and typescript, [1958] (Box 46, Folder 1029)
      - English translation - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1958] (Box 46, Folder 1030-32)
      - English translation - final version, typescript carbon, 1958 (Box 47, Folder 1033-34)
      - Advertisements and Book reviews, 1949-60 (Box 47, Folder 1035)
    - "Rebel in a World of Platitudes"
      See: Subject Files - Nathalie Sarraute
      - - Clippings, Box 48 folder 1059
    - Le Silence - Le Mensonge
      - Notes from French text, 1967 (Box 47, Folder 1036)
      - English translation notebook, holograph, corrected, [1969] (Box 47, Folder 1037)
      - English translation, typescript carbon, [1969] (Box 47, Folder 1038)
      - Book review, 1967 Feb 20 (Box 47, Folder 1039)
    - Tropismes
      See: Bachelard, Gaston - "Poétique
      - de l'espace" - English translation notebook, Box 43, folder 960
    - Vous les entendez
      - English translation notebook, typescript, corrected, [1972] (Box 47, Folder 1040)
    - [Various works]
      - Publishers' correspondence, 1949-69 (Box 47, Folder 1041-43)
        Includes: John Lehman, Bernard Frechtman, André Spire, James Laughlin, Dionys Mascolo, M. Schebeko, Stella Weideman, Hugh Weideman, Anita Tenzer, André Sauret, George Braziller, John Calder, Philip Rahv, James Stern, Stuart Gilbert, Sylvia Beach, Richard Howard, Arthur Crook, and Nathalie Sarraute
      - General translation notes, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1044)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul
    - The Wall
      - English translation, printed version Chimera, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 1045)
  - Schwartz, Laurent
    - "Three Weeks in Vietnam"
      - English translation, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1046)
  - Sprigge, Elizabeth
    - Ionesco à Londres
      - French text, typescript, corrected, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 1047)
      - English translation, typescript, 1960
  - Triolet, Elsa
    - "Yvette"
      - English translation, typescript carbon, corrected, [1946] (Box 48, Folder 1048)
  - Valéry, Paul
    - "Young Man of Our Time"
      - English translation, Harper's Bazaar, 1945 Sep (Box 48, Folder 1049)
  - Vidal-Naquet, Pierre
    - "The Greek Mirage and the French Revolution"
      - English translation, typescript photocopy, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 1050)
    - "The Immortal Slaves of Athena Ilias"
      - English translation, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1051)
    - Journal de la commune étudiante
      - Correspondence [including Pierre Vidal- Naquet], 1971 (Box 48, Folder 1052)
      - Notes, n.d.
      - English translation pages, typescript, [1971] (Box 48, Folder 1053)
      - Book reviews, 1972
    - A Paper Eichmann
      - Correspondence, 1980, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 1054)
        [Includes: Robert Silvers]
      - Background material - Memoire en défense by Robert Faurisson, photocopy of introduction by Noam Chomsky (Box 48, Folder 1055)
      - French text, [1980] (Box 48, Folder 1056)
      - English translation notebook, holograph, [1980] (Box 48, Folder 1057)
      - English translation, typescript, corrected, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 1058)
      - Clippings
        - Faurisson affair, 1980-81 (Box 48, Folder 1059)
        - Holocaust, 1980-81 (Box 48, Folder 1060)
        - Jews and France, 1982 (Box 48, Folder 1061)
    - "Plato's Myth of the Statesman, the Ambiguities of the Golden Age and of History"
      - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 1062)
      - Notes, [1978]
      - English translation, typescript, corrected, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 1063)
      - English translation proof sheet, typescript, corrected, 1978
    - "The Shields of the Heroes"
      - English translation notebook, holograph, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1064)
    - [Unidentified texts]
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1064a)
  - Weil, Simone
    - "Hector"
      - English translation, typescript carbon, [1946] (Box 48, Folder 1065)
  - Unidentified
    - Sur Daumier
      - English translation notebook, holograph, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1066)
  - Miscellaneous
    - [EMPTY FOLDER], n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1067)
    - Scott Moncrieff Prize Correspondence, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 1068)
    - Acceptance speech with biographical notes, 1971
- Maria Jolas - Subject Files, 1921-1986; Series X; 4.25; (8 boxes)
  Series X is divided into ten subseries. Each subseries in arranged alphabetically by subject of material, by author, or by title.
  - Amerindians history
    - Akwesasne Notes, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 1069)
    - Clipping, 1980 Jan 19
    - L'Histoire, 1980 Jan (Box 49, Folder 1070)
    - Reports on Amerindians, 1979-80
  - Arp, Jean
    - Sculpture catalog questionnaire, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1071)
  - Chomsky, Noam
    - Clipping, 1974 Apr 20 (Box 49, Folder 1072)
    - Counter-Revolutionary Violence: Bloodbaths in Fact and Propaganda, 1973
  - Duthuit, Claude
    - School records and receipts (Box 49, Folder 1073)
  - Franckenstein, Joseph
    - Editorials, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 1074)
  - Jolas, Jacques
    - Clippings, 1939-41 (Box 49, Folder 1075)
    - Le Ménestrel, 1923 Oct 26
    - Menu, 1945 Aug 15 (Box 49, Folder 1076)
    - Programs, 1921-54
  - Joyce, James
    - Articles
      - American Book Collector - James Joyce Number, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 1077)
      - The Analyst [issues], 1955-62 (Box 49, Folder 1078)
      - Armstrong, Alison
        - "Excerpts from The Language of Exile: Work in Progress typescript photocopy [with letter], 1976 Nov 6 (Box 49, Folder 1079)
      - Atherton, J. S.
        - "Body and Soul and Blood and Ouns" Times Literary Supplement, 1976 Apr 23 (Box 49, Folder 1080)
        - "Joyce James" Encyclopedia Britannica offprint, 1974
        - "The Oxen of the Sun," James Joyce's Ulysses chapter offprint [with letter], n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1081)
      - Benstock, Bernard
        - "A Setdown Secular Phoenish: The Finn of Finnegan's Wake ," typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1082)
      - Benstock, Shari
        - "The Double Image of Modernism: Matisse's Etchings for Ulysses " Contemporary Literature offprint, autographed, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 1083)
        - "Narrative in Ulysses: 3rd and 4th levels" [panel transcript], typescript photocopy, 1976 Nov 20
      - Brivic, Sheldon
        - "Contribution to Panel on the Validity of the Psychoanalytic Approach to Joyce," typescript photocopy, 1977 Jun 15 (Box 49, Folder 1084)
      - Burgess, Anthony
        - "Joyce 100 Years On" Observer Review, 1982 Jam 31 (Box 49, Folder 1085)
      - Caws, Mary Ann
        - "Joyce in Partial Perspective: A Rereading of Figures" Comparative Literature Studies offprint [autographed], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 1086)
      - Church, Margaret
        - "Joycean Structure in Jacob's Room and Mrs. Dalloway " International Fiction Review photocopy [autographed], 1977 (Box 49, Folder 1087)
      - Cixous, Hélène
        - "Avant-portrait ou la bifurcation d'une vocation" typescript photocopy, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 1088)
        - "Exiles ou les vertus de malheur," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d.
        - "Portrait de sa femme par l'artiste," printed version Les Lettres Nouvelles, 1966 Mar (Box 49, Folder 1089)